[
    {
        "question": "Q1: Web is a huge collection 0f ________ of information linked to each other around the globe.",
        "a": " pages",
        "b": " websites",
        "c": " html",
        "d": " None of the above",
        "ans": "ans1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q2: ________ is known as the father of World Wide Web.",
        "a": " John T. Thomson",
        "b": " Dinis Ritchie",
        "c": " Tim Berners-Lee",
        "d": " None of the above",
        "ans": "ans3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q3: ________ is a set of rules; that is used to communicate applications to each other.",
        "a": " HTML",
        "b": " Website",
        "c": " Protocol",
        "d": " XML",
        "ans": "ans3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q4: ________ is the Primary protocol used to distribute information on the web.",
        "a": " TCP/IP",
        "b": " HTTP",
        "c": " FTP",
        "d": " Telnet",
        "ans": "ans2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q5: All the components which are visible in website are ________.",
        "a": " objects",
        "b": " lists",
        "c": " files",
        "d": " classes",
        "ans": "ans1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q6: There are _______ types of web team.",
        "a": " three",
        "b": " four",
        "c": " one",
        "d": " two",
        "ans": "ans4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q7: Category of web sites are ________.",
        "a": " corporate type website",
        "b": " individual website",
        "c": " both A and B",
        "d": " None of the above",
        "ans": "ans3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q8: ________ creates the look and feel of the site.",
        "a": " Creative Lead",
        "b": " Programmer ",
        "c": " Analyst",
        "d": " Designer",
        "ans": "ans4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q9: What does HTML stand for?",
        "a": " Hyper Text Preprocessor",
        "b": " Hyper Text Markup Language",
        "c": " Hyper Tool Multiple Language",
        "d": " Hyper Tool Multi Language ",
        "ans": "ans2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q10: What does CSS stand for?",
        "a": " Cascading Style Sheet",
        "b": " Colorful Style Sheet",
        "c": " Computer Style Sheet",
        "d": " Common Style Sheet",
        "ans": "ans1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q11: What does XML stands for?",
        "a": " eXecutable Markup Language",
        "b": " eXtra Multi-program Language",
        "c": " eXtensible Markup Language",
        "d": " eXamine Multiple Language",
        "ans": "ans3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q12: What does PHP stand for?",
        "a": " Hypertext Programming",
        "b": " Hypertext preprogramming",
        "c": " Hypertext Preprocessor",
        "d": " None of the above",
        "ans": "ans3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q13: What does SQL stand for?",
        "a": " Stylish Question Language",
        "b": " Statement Query Language",
        "c": " Structured Question Language",
        "d": " None of the above",
        "ans": "ans4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q14: Which one of the following language dynamically create pages on a web server.?",
        "a": " HTML",
        "b": " PHP",
        "c": " JavaScript",
        "d": " None of the above",
        "ans": "ans2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q15: Which one of the following language dynamically create interactive and programmable web pages?",
        "a": " C",
        "b": " C++",
        "c": " JavaScript",
        "d": " None of the above",
        "ans": "ans3"
    }
]